The Great Mage Flamme's grimoire?
大魔法使弗蘭梅的魔導書？
All books said to be written by Flamme are known to be fake.
所有據稱是弗蘭梅的著作都是假的
All of the grimoires they've discovered have been counterfeits.
至今找到的所有魔導書也都是贗品
This might be the best counterfeit I've ever seen.
這本大概是我看過做得最好的了
It's not a bad reward for a subjugation quest.
就討伐任務的報酬而言也算不錯了
I have no idea what's good about that.
我看不出來這樣哪裡不錯了
But when there are so many fake ones out there,
但贗品數量這麼多
you start to doubt if a real one really exists.
都讓人不禁懷疑是否真的有真品
The existence of Flamme, the founder of humanity's magic,
有人類魔法始祖之稱的弗蘭梅本身
is like a fairy tale in itself.
就像童話故事中的人物一樣
A fairy tale, huh?
童話故事嗎？
I guess so…
說得也是
That goes to show how much time has passed.
時間都已經過去那麼久了
I'm probably the only one who remembers
還能記得她樣貌的人
what she looked like.
大概只有我了
It's morning?
早上了？
Mistress Frieren woke up early!
芙莉蓮大人居然早起了！
Is that a big deal?
有什麼了不起的嗎？
Of course it is.
當然很了不起啊
You have to commend her when this happens.
這種時候必須好好嘉獎一番
What's going on?
這是怎樣？
ORIGINAL STORY BY KANEHITO YAMADA / TSUKASA ABE
（原作：山田鐘人，作畫：阿部司）
28 YEARS FROM THE DEATH OF HIMMEL THE HERO
（勇者欣梅爾逝世的28年後）
ENG ROAD IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
（北方諸國，安格街道）
What a lifesaver.
真是幫了大忙了
With this road blocked, I was completely out of options.
這條路堵住了 我都不知道該怎麼辦了
Hey…
我說…
Do we have to do this?
我們有必要做這件事嗎？
Are you not happy with it? The reward is not bad.
你不滿意嗎？報酬還不錯啊
That's not what I mean.
我不是這個意思
Can't you magically move the wagon to the other side?
不是可以直接用魔法 把馬車搬到另外一邊嗎？
That won't be helpful for others who pass through.
這樣後面要過的人還是過不了
That's what Fern said.
費倫是這麼說的
You're so selfish, Stark.
你只有考慮自己呢，修塔爾克
You're the last person who can say that.
最沒資格說這種話的就是妳了吧
-Thank you for your hard work. -Oh, thanks.
-各位辛苦了 -謝了
By the way…
話說回來
why is there so much rubble here?
到底哪來這麼多碎石啊？
In the northern lands,
在北方諸國
some areas are still in a state of war with demons.
有些地區還在跟魔族打仗
This must be the effects of that.
十有八九是這個緣故
The aftermath of war, huh?
戰爭造成的嗎？
Master Stark,
修塔爾克大人
can you leave that side for later and help me with this please?
你可以放下那邊，先過來幫我嗎？
Master Stark?
修塔爾克大人？
Hey, can you stop calling me "Master Stark"?
那個，妳能不能 別再叫我“修塔爾克大人”？
It makes me uncomfortable.
我聽了很不自在
We're almost the same age, right?
我們不是差不多大嗎？
I see… All right.
這樣啊，我明白了
Stark, hurry up and help me. Chop chop!
修塔爾克，快過來幫我，動作快！
So bossy!
也太隨便了吧！
That's not what I meant.
我又不是這個意思
There are other ways.
還有其他方式啊
-Other honorifics that you can use. -Right…
-有其他有禮貌點的方式吧 -是喔…
Also, try to be a little more friendly.
而且可以再溫柔一點吧
I get hurt easily.
我很玻璃心的
-This guy is such a pain. -"This guy"?
-這傢伙真是麻煩 -“這傢伙”都出來了
Are you getting work done?
你們那邊還順利嗎？
Let's hurry up, Master Stark.
要加快動作了，修塔爾克大人
Yes…
好…
Wow, thank you so much.
太謝謝各位了
If you don't mind, I can show you the way to town.
如果你們不嫌棄的話 我可以為各位帶路
An elf, huh?
不過您是精靈族吧？
I've been alive for a long time, but you're the first one I've ever met.
我活了這麼一大把年紀 您還是我第一個見到的精靈
I guess we're pretty rare.
畢竟精靈很罕見
Now that you mention it, I have never met
這麼說起來，我還沒見過
an elf other than Mistress Frieren.
芙莉蓮大人以外的精靈
We're small in number.
精靈族的人數很少
I've only met a handful of fellow elves myself.
就連我自己見過的同族也沒幾個
Elves live for a long time,
精靈族的壽命很長
but we've lost all things like romantic feelings
但我們沒有戀愛這類的情感
and reproductive instincts.
生殖本能也有缺陷
We're slowly becoming extinct.
已經慢慢步入滅絕了
The last time I met a fellow elf was more than 400 years ago.
上次見到同族 也已經是四百年以前的事了
Our end may be nearer than I thought.
也許會比我預期的更早滅絕呢
We can see the town now.
可以看到城市了
There's a line of wagons.
有很多馬車在排隊呢
Those are merchants.
那些都是商人
Tonight is the Liberation Festival.
今晚是解放祭
Today was the day Himmel the Hero and his party
今天是勇者欣梅爾一行人
defeated the demon that had control over this region.
將支配這個地區的魔族打敗的日子
Did we do something like that?
好像是有過這麼一件事
The Liberation Festival is a commemoration of that day.
解放祭是為了紀念那一天所舉辦的
We decorate the statues of Master Himmel and his party in the town square
我們會裝飾廣場中 欣梅爾大人一行人的銅像
and the entire town joins in a grand celebration.
整座城的人都會加入這場盛大的慶典
Humans are so over the top.
人類真是愛小題大作
They turn everything into a festival.
什麼事都可以變成慶典
The demon was defeated more than 80 years ago.
魔族被擊敗已經是八十年前的事了
That's enough time
這樣的時間
for humans to forget about something.
已經長到足夠 讓人類把一些事情忘記了
Despite that,
儘管如此
even if it's just this one day,
每每到了這一天
everyone remembers what Master Himmel and his party did.
大家還是會記起 欣梅爾大人一行人的功績
Yes, splendid job.
嗯，做得很漂亮
Five retakes, huh?
重做了五次嗎？
It ended early this time.
這次比較早結束呢
Himmel, you're always making statues of yourself.
欣梅爾，你總是 要別人製作你的銅像呢
I want everyone to remember.
我想要大家都能記住我
Unlike you, we won't live very long.
畢竟我們不像妳能活那麼久
I have to let the future generations know how handsome I am.
必須要讓後代子孫知道我有多帥嘛
Let's return to the inn.
差不多該回旅店了
But the biggest reason is…
不過最重要的理由是…
so that you're not left all alone in the future.
讓妳以後不會感到孤單
What?
什麼意思啊？
It's not a fairy tale.
我們不是童話故事
We existed in real life.
而是真實存在過的
Like this, we commemorate the deeds
我們每年都會像這樣
of Himmel the Hero and his party each year.
紀念勇者欣梅爾一行人的豐功偉業
Now that I look at it, you look just like the statue
現在這麼一看，您跟勇者一行人中的
of Mistress Frieren from the party of heroes.
芙莉蓮大人還蠻像的
Will this still be held 100 years from now?
一百年後還會繼續舉辦這個慶典嗎？
As long as this town exists.
只要這座城市還在的話就會辦
How about 1,000 years?
那麼一千年後呢？
That… I can't say for sure.
那…我就不敢保證了
All right, let's go.
好，出發
To the northernmost point we go.
往北方的盡頭前進
Now that I think about it,
我現在才想到
I never asked about the destination of this journey.
我還沒問過這趟旅途的目的地
Where is it?
我們要去哪裡？
Heaven.
天國
That sounds fun.
聽起來很有趣啊
28 YEARS FROM THE DEATH OF HIMMEL THE HERO
（勇者欣梅爾逝世的28年後）
GRAF GRANAT'S DOMAIN IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
（北方諸國，古拉納特伯爵領地）
There are so many guards.
好多衛兵喔
Did something happen?
發生過什麼事嗎？
Anyway, let's just decide who is going to buy what.
總之先決定各自要採買的東西吧
Mistress Frieren, we're in the middle of the town.
芙莉蓮大人，我們可是在城裡啊
It's a demon.
是魔族
What are you doing!
妳在做什麼！
Graf Granat,
古拉納特伯爵
did you plan this?
這是出自你的手筆嗎？
Lord Lügner,
琉古納殿下
it is true that I despise you enough to want to kill you.
我確實對魔族恨不得殺之而後快
However,
但是
I am not foolish enough to kill a messenger of peace
我還沒有蠢到會在光天化日之下
in broad daylight.
對和談使者出手的地步
Messenger of peace?
和談使者？
She's most likely an adventurer who doesn't know our situation.
她很可能是個沒搞清楚狀況的冒險者
I'll take your word for it.
既然你這麼說，就當作是這樣吧
You have calm, cold eyes filled with murderous intent.
妳的眼神很平靜、冷酷又充滿殺意呢
Even the citizens of this town who despise us
就連城市裡痛恨我們的百姓
look at me as a human,
看到我雖然會怕
albeit with fear.
但至少把我當成人來看待
But you look at me as if you are looking at a beast.
但是妳看我的眼神 就好像在看一頭猛獸一樣
And that's what you are.
事實就是如此啊
You demons mimic human voices but you're nothing but
魔族只會模仿人類的聲音
beasts with whom we cannot communicate.
實際上卻是無法溝通的猛獸
Put her in the dungeon.
把她關進宅邸的地牢
Yes, sir.
是
Huh?
什麼？
Hey!
喂！
I'm bored.
好閒啊
Mistress Frieren…
芙莉蓮大人…
They said to repent for two to three years.
他們說要讓妳反省個兩、三年呢
That's shorter than I thought.
比我預期的來得短呢
Bring me a grimoire later.
晚點幫我把魔導書拿過來吧
Mistress Frieren, you really love to waste time, don't you?
芙莉蓮大人真的很愛浪費時間呢
I'm not here because I want to be.
我又不是自願被關進來的
So, why are they calling demons "messengers of peace"?
話說回來 為什麼稱呼那個魔族為和談使者？
We did some research while doing our shopping.
我們採購時順便調查了一下
You know Aura the Guillotine, right?
您知道斷頭台阿烏拉吧？
The greater demon and one of the Seven Sages of Destruction, right?
是大魔族七崩賢中的其中一人吧？
While fighting with us,
跟我們對戰時
she lost most of her servants and went missing.
她失去大部分的部下後就銷聲匿跡了
Did something happen recently?
最近發生了什麼事嗎？
Aura regained power 28 years ago.
阿烏拉28年前就恢復力量了
This town has
這座城市
been fighting with her army for a long time, apparently.
看來已經跟她的軍隊 交戰了很長一段時間
But Aura, who became tired of meaningless massacres,
不過阿烏拉開始 受不了沒有意義的殺戮
requested peace be made.
就提出了要求和談
And so they accepted her messengers of peace?
所以就接見了她的和談使者？
That was a bad move.
這步棋下錯了呢
It's futile to talk to demons.
跟魔族對話根本沒有用
It can't be totally futile. We have the ability to speak.
不會完全沒有用吧 畢竟我們有交談的能力啊
If we can settle things by negotiating, that will be best.
如果可以靠協商解決問題的話 那就再好不過了
We can't settle things, that's why it's futile.
就是因為解決不了才沒有用
Demons are human-eating creatures.
魔族是以人為食的生物
Have you ever wondered why they use the same language as mankind?
你有想過他們為什麼 會使用跟人類相同的語言嗎？
My Hero, kill it at once!
勇者大人，快給他最後一擊！
It's still a child.
他還只是個孩子
So what if it is?
那又怎樣？
It ate our daughter alive!
他可是生吞了我們女兒啊！
It hurts…
好痛…
Mom…
媽媽…
That's enough. I will do it.
好了，我來吧
At this rate, we're the same as demons.
這麼做的話，我們也跟魔族沒有兩樣
It's not like they cannot survive without eating humans, right?
他們並非不吃人就活不下去吧？
Why don't we give it a chance to atone?
何不給他一個贖罪的機會？
Chief…
村長…
Don't be ridiculous!
開什麼玩笑！
My daughter… Give me back my daughter!
我的女兒…把我女兒還給我！
Let's treat your wounds.
先治療一下傷口吧
I was just looking for someone to help me in the field.
剛好我田裡正缺人手
Himmel, if you don't kill it now, you will regret it.
欣梅爾 現在不動手的話，你會後悔的
After all, it--
他畢竟是…
Frieren, we have the ability to speak.
芙莉蓮，我們有交談的能力
We'll be staying in this village anyway.
反正還要在村裡待上一陣子
Let's see how it goes.
不妨就看看會怎樣吧
I see…
這樣啊…
Why did you kill the chief?
你為什麼殺了村長？
I knew it.
我就知道
We should have killed it back then.
當時我們就應該殺了他
There you go again.
又來了
I could feel your murderous intent every day.
我每天都能感受到妳的殺意
I want to live peacefully.
我只想安穩地過生活
That's why I prepared this.
所以準備了這個
This will replace
這個可以取代
your daughter that I ate.
被我吃掉的妳的女兒
She is the chief's daughter.
她是村長的女兒
The chief is gone now.
村長已經不在了
It seems as though I made the wrong decision.
看來我好像做了錯誤的決定
Oh well, I'll use her as a hostage--
沒辦法了，我就把她當成人質…
You won't stop me now, right?
你現在不會攔我了吧？
No…
不會了
Mom…
媽媽…
"Mom" again, huh?
又說了“媽媽”呢
Like monsters, child-rearing is not a part of demon culture.
魔族就跟魔物一樣 沒有養育子女的習性
After they are born, they spend most of their time alone.
他們從出生開始 幾乎都是在孤獨中渡過
Solitude is part of your nature
孤獨已經是你們天性的一部份
and the concept of family doesn't exist for you.
你們根本沒有家庭這種概念
So why
所以說
do you use the word, "Mom"?
你為什麼會說出“媽媽”這個詞呢？
That way
這樣一來
you can't kill me.
妳就下不了手殺我了吧
It's a beautiful word that works like magic.
這個詞簡直跟魔法一樣美妙呢
To them, words are just tools for deceiving mankind.
對他們而言 語言只是拿來欺騙人類的工具
The Great Mage Flamme
大魔法使弗蘭梅
defined demons as monsters who can speak.
將魔族定義為會說話的魔物
They're descendants of monsters who would
他們是魔物的子孫，會藏身於黑暗中
hide in the shadows and say, "help me" to lure in prey.
發出“救救我”這種話語來引誘獵物
Bring me gifts.
書就拜託了
Graf Granat is late.
古拉納特伯爵真慢
It's a diplomatic strategy of mankind.
這是人類的外交手段
More than that, I'm curious about that mage.
比起這些，我對那個魔法使更感興趣
That face is so familiar…
那張臉很面熟…
Beasts with whom we cannot communicate, huh?
無法溝通的猛獸嗎？
What a perfect way to put it.
真是貼切的形容
She is the only one in this town
她是這座城裡
who understands the true nature of us demons.
唯一清楚我們魔族本質的人
There is only one reason for predators
以人為食的掠食者
who prey on humans to speak the human language.
會說人類的語言的理由只有一個
They aren't words for mutual understanding
這些語言不是用來互相理解
but words for deception.
而是用來欺騙
This town won't last very long.
看來這座城維持不了多久了
I'll escape once the chaos ensues.
我看還是趁亂出逃吧
And this is?
這裡是？
My son's room.
這裡是我兒子的房間
He was such a good kid.
他是個優秀的孩子
He would always say that he'd soon take over
他總是說他很快就會
as head of the family and let me take it easy.
成為一家之主，好讓我能卸下重擔
When he fought a match before the king, he was bestowed with this sword.
他在御前比試時，陛下賜給他這把劍
Where is your son now?
令郎現在在哪裡呢？
He died ten years ago, in the battle with Aura.
十年前死在跟阿烏拉的戰鬥中了
All that returned was this sword.
回來的只有這把劍
Lügner!
琉古納！
I only allowed you in so I could avenge my son.
之所以讓你們踏進家門 就是為了給我兒子報仇
I will kill all of you messengers here.
我要殺了所有和談使者
Your peace negotiations can kiss my ass!
什麼和談？想都別想！
This room has been thoroughly cleaned.
這個房間一塵不染呢
I bet it hasn't changed at all from ten years ago.
我想應該還跟十年前一樣吧
What about it?
那又怎樣？
I also keep my father's room the way it was when he was
我也把我父親的房間 維持的跟以前一樣
killed by you people.
他也死在你們人類的手中
Why don't we stop this, Graf Granat?
我們何不終止這一切呢 古拉納特伯爵？
Or do you want to continue shedding blood
還是說你希望繼續血流成河
and bring more sadness upon people?
讓人們繼續悲痛不已呢？
We have the ability to speak.
我們擁有交談的能力
Please give us an opportunity to talk it out.
請給我們一個機會和談
Show them to the drawing room.
帶他們去會客室
I need to think about it.
我需要好想想
Master Lügner,
琉古納大人
what is a "father"?
“父親”是什麼？
Who knows?
誰知道？
Graf Granat seems to have a grudge against us,
看來古拉納特伯爵對我們恨之入骨
but he also seems to be empathetic.
但他也是個重情重義的人
If we can get him on our side,
如果可以拉攏他
we can make him remove the defense barrier as a sign of peace.
就可以用和平象徵為由 讓他撤掉防護結界
Then Mistress Aura's army
阿烏拉大人的軍隊
will destroy this town.
就能摧毀這座城了
By the way, Linie,
對了，莉妮耶
I don't see Draht anywhere.
怎麼沒看到多拉特的蹤影？
He said he'd get rid of a nuisance.
他說他要去解決礙事的傢伙
He got ahead of himself.
被他搶先一步了
Young ones are so hot‐blooded. What can I do?
年輕氣盛的傢伙真讓人頭痛
Lord Draht!
多拉特閣下！
We cannot have you in a place like this.
我們不能讓您進去這種地方
Please return--
請回…
Who are you? It's outside of visiting hours.
你是誰？已經過了訪客時間了
I am Draht, a servant
我是多拉特
and executioner of Aura the Guillotine.
是斷頭臺阿烏拉的手下與斬首吏
I'm here to kill you.
我是來殺妳的
I see.
這樣啊
You're done playing diplomat?
外交遊戲已經玩完了？
It's just beginning.
才剛開始而已
According to Lord Lügner,
根據琉古納大人所言
this girl is our only obstacle.
這個少女是我們唯一的阻礙
If I get rid of her,
如果能除掉她
all we have to do is win over Graf Granat
接下來只要拉攏古拉納特伯爵
and this town will easily fall.
就能輕而易舉地攻陷這座城
Just to let you know, I'm strong.
話先說在前頭，我可是很強的
Stronger than me?
比我強嗎？
Stronger than Aura the Guillotine.
比斷頭台的阿烏拉強
Who is that mage?
那個魔法使到底是誰？
Killing a guard is
殺掉衛兵
worthy of capital punishment.
是很重的罪
The mage who has killed
史上葬送過
the most demons in history.
最多魔族的魔法使
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻譯：洪貞韻